02-04
Machine Learning
<Supervised Machine Learning>
Data => Fit & Train => Model


<Unsupervised Machine Learning>
Identify groups of data shares same traits
Data => UML Algorithm => Model

<Supervised Machine Learning>
Value prediction
Needs training data containing value being predicted
Trained model predicts value in new data
Subject of this course

<Unsupervised Machine Learning>
Identify clusters of like data
Data does not contain cluster membership
Model provides access to data by cluster
Not in this course

Numpy scientific computing
Pandas data frames
Matplotlib 2d plotting
Scikit-learn algorithms, pre-processing, performance evaluation

www.continuum.io/downloads

09 machine learning workflow
Asking the right question
Preparing data
Selecting the algorithm
Training the model
Testing the model

10 - From Question to Solution Statement

Define scope (including data sources)
Define target performance
Define context for usage
Define how solution will be created

11 - Introduction to Data Preparation
Find the data we need
Inspect and clean th data
Explore the data
Mold the data to tidy data
Demos in python

<Tidy data>
Tidy data sets are easy to manipulate, model and visualize, and have a specific structure:
Each variable is a column
Each obervation is a row
Each type of observational unit is a table

12 - Getting Data.mp4

Google
Government databases
Professional or company data sources
Your company
Your department

14 - Loading, Cleaning, and Inspecting Data
Loading data
Exploring data
Cleaning data

import pandas as pd 
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt 
import lumpy as np

## Loading and Reviewing the Data
df = pd.read_csv(\"./data/pima-data.csv\")

df.shape #display number of rows, number of columns

df.head #秀出前幾row, head 看資料長怎樣，rows, colums從0開始
df.tail #秀出最後幾幾row, 和 head 看資料長怎樣，rows, colums從0開始

#檢查有沒有任何null value
df.isnull().values.any()
    """
    def plot_corr(df, size=11):
    
    Function plots a graphical correlation matrix for each pair of columns in the dataframe.
    
    Input:\n",
    df: pandas DataFrame\n",
    size: vertical and horizontal size of the plot\n",
    
    Displays:\n",
    matrix of correlation between columns.  Blue-cyan-yellow-red-darkred => less to more correlated\n",
    "                                                0 ------------------>  1\n",
    "                                                Expect a darkred line running from top left to bottom right\n",
    """
   
    corr = df.corr()    # data frame correlation function\n",
    fig, ax = plt.subplots(figsize=(size, size))
    ax.matshow(corr)   # color code the rectangles by correlation value\n",
    plt.xticks(range(len(corr.columns)), corr.columns)  # draw x tick marks\n",
    plt.yticks(range(len(corr.columns)), corr.columns)  # draw y tick marks\n"

plot_corr(df) #找出相關性
df.corr() #秀出每行每列的相關性

15 - Molding Data
Adjusting data types
Creating new columns, if required

#把true, false轉成1跟0
df.head(5)
diabetes_map = {True : 1, False : 0}
df['diabetes']=dfdf['diabetes'].map(diabetes_map)
df.head(5)


#count true/false的次數/ratio
num_true = len(df.loc[df['diabetes'] == True])
num_false = len(df.loc[df['diabetes'] == False])
print(\"Number of True cases:  {0} ({1:2.2f}%)\".format(num_true, (num_true/num_true + num_false) * 100))
print(\"Number of False cases: {0} ({1:2.2f}%)\".format(num_false, (num_false/num_true + num_false) * 100))

16 - The Role of the Algorithm
<Regression>
Continuous values

<Classification>
Discrete values
Small, medium, large
1-100, 101-200, 201-300
True or false

<Complexity>
Keep it Simple
Eliminate "ensemble" algorithms
- container algorithm
- multiple child algorithms
- boost performance
- can be difficult to debug


17 - Narrowing the Selection


18 - Selecting Our Initial Algorithm

<Naive bayes>
Based on likelihood and probability
Every feature has the same weight
Requires smaller amount of data

<Logistic Regression> 
Binary result
Relationship between features and weighted

<Decision Tress>
Binary Tree
Node contains decision
Requires enough data to determine nodes and splits

19 - Introduction to Training
20 - The Training Process
分出兩群data
21 - Python Training Tools
Scikit-learn: NumPy, SciPy, Pandas

22 - Splitting Data and Training the Algorithm

import pandas as pd                 # pandas is a dataframe library\n",
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt      # matplotlib.pyplot plots data\n",

df = pd.read_csv(\"./data/pima-data.csv\")
from sklearn.cross_validation import train_test_split

<Missing data>
Ignore
Drop observations 
Replace values
Replace with mean, median
Replace with expert knowledge derived value
Using mean imputing

From sklearn.preprocessing import Imputer



23 - Introduction to Evaluating the Model
24 - Evaluating the Naive Bayes Model
25 - Performance Improvement, Take 1
Adjust current algorithm
Get more data or improve data
Improve training
Switch algorithms

Random Forest
Fits multiple trees with subsets of data
Averages tree results to improve performance and control overfitting

From sklearn.ensemble import RandomForestClassifier

26 - Why Overfitting Is Bad
Regularization hyperparameter
Cross validation
Sacrifice some perfection for better overall performance

27 - Performance Improvement, Take 2
Adjust current algorithm
Get more data or improve data
Improve training
Switch algorithms

28 - Understanding and Fixing Unbalanced Classes
More of one class than the others
Can be causing biases estimation yielding poor prediction results

29 - What Is Cross Validation.mp4	
Training, validation, testing

How do we choose the validation data?
What if we don't have enough data?
Does this approach mitigate overtraining?

<K-fold cross validation>
切成小塊 一塊用為validation data

For each fold: Determine best hyper parameter value
Next: Set model hyper parameter value to average best

30 - Implementing and Evaluating Cross Validatition
31 - Summarizing the Evaluation


Source: PL Understanding Machine Learning With Python